Hello! Welcome in the next episode of Bug
Bounty Reports Explained.
Today you'll learn how Augusto
Zanellato accidentally
found a bug that allowed him
to add a backdoor to Shopify.
Make sure to stick until the end,
because I will show you step by step
how you can check
the contents of Electron application
no matter what platform you use.
Links to the original report and Augusto's
media are in the description.
Enjoy! Electron is a Node.js
framework that allows building
desktop applications
using the same technologies
as when developing websites.
Visual Studio Code, Slack, Discord
or WhatsApp are all built using Electron.
The minimalistic
hello word app doesn't need much files.
However, when you want to distribute,
your application, files
must have a specific structure.
In case of this report,
the app was packaged for Mac OS system.
You can use electron-packager module.
This is the command that I used
to package my application.
These options are not relevant
for this part, at least not yet.
Then you need to create a
single .DMG file using yet another module.
After you mount it,
you can finally use the application.
It's inside /Volumes directory.
Let's browse it.
The binary is inside
Contents/macOS directory.
For us, however, the most important
is the Resources dir. Inside,
you have the app folder that contains
all the files from your application.
However, the application
that is the cause of
this vulnerability
did not have such directory.
Instead, it had app.asar file.
It's an Electron archive.
It concatenates all the files
from your application into a single file.
Somewhat like tar,
but without compression.
To modify my application
so that it also uses asar file
I had to add --asar flag
to electron-packager command.
But what's the purpose of that?
To answer that question, I took a look
into the Electron documentation.
Until the 2nd December
2020, the documentation said
"you can also package your app
into an asar archive
to avoid exposing your app's
source code to users".
Which was not true.
You can easily extract
the contents of the archive
using "npx asar extract" command.
Using this file format
does not protect the code in any way.
The documentation was changed
only two months prior to this bug.
Now it says "you can package
you app into an asar archive
to improve the performance of reading
files on platforms like Windows".
It's very interesting
how misguiding it was.
If you enjoy that I dig deep
to find out such information
make sure to like this video right now.
Let's come back to our hunter.
He downloaded the application
and was analyzing it.
The name of the application
is not disclosed
but it was a random application
from the Internet and the hunter
did not know it was related
to Shopify in any way.
He just wanted to see how it works.
So he started to review the contents
of the application,
including the asar archive.
Inside, he found .env file. What is that?
One of the most popular
npm packages is dotenv.
It automatically loads
environment variables
from .env file into process.env.
So when you had TEST
the variable in the .env
file, it's automatically loaded
into the process.env.TEST.
We can't be 100% sure
this application did use this package,
but one way or another,
it used environmental variables
from the .env file.
Inside, among other credentials,
the hunter found a GH_TOKEN variable.
As you might guess,
it was a GitHub rest API token.
Augusto confirmed its valid
by hitting /user endpoint.
At this point, it was only affecting
the developer who created the application,
and nothing foreshadowed
that it affected Shopify in any way.
Then, he tried to
query /user/orgs endpoint.
And saw that this developer was a member
of Shopify organization on GitHub.
So it was looking
very promising at that point.
As the next step,
he queried /orgs/shopify/repos.
And what he saw was the list of many
public and private Shopify
repositories with pull and push access.
The impact of this is huge.
You can read all the code of Shopify
closed-source repositories,
but also you can commit a backdoor
to it, stealing millions of dollars
and personal information
of millions of Shopify customers.
The Shopify team was quick
to respond on Hackerone.
The report was triaged
as critical the same day
and the $50,000 bounty
was awarded a week later.
How you can test for this bug?
After downloading .DMG file,
you can unpack it using 7z command
both on Mac OS and on Linux
or using 7zip program on Windows.
Then, you browse to the Contents/Resources
and you run "npx asar
extract app.asar app".
Then you will have the sources
of the application and you can review them
as you normally would.
What an amazing bug!
I also interviewed Agusto in my Bug
Bounty Reports Discussed podcast.
Among others, you can hear about why
did he choose to review this application
or what was his and his friend's
reaction to finding
the $50,000 bug by accident.
The podcast will be published shortly
after this video
so make sure to subscribe
to Bug Bounty Reports Discussed
in your favorite podcasting up
or here on YouTube, if you prefer.
Links are in the description.
For now, thank you
for watching and goodbye!